达里恩
Darrien?
总监：
zlean  sephiroth_8
怎么回事
What the hell happened?
你得去医院
We got to get you to a hospital.
不  你是医生  把伤口缝好就行
No, you're a doctor. Just stitch me up.
没那么简单  我们得...
It's more complicated than that. We need to--
警察会在医院等我
The cops will be waiting for me at the hospital.
他们会认定我是从犯
They're gonna bust me back inside
把我送回监狱
just for being with felons.
让你待在这  我也会被抓
You stay here, they bust me.
我不能回去  莱米
I can't go back, Remy.
我也不能  上帝保佑你别死
Neither can I. God forbid you die,
不然我就是过失杀人
I'm up for manslaughter.
我去找别人
I'll find someone else.
你这么出去  会大量失血
You leave, you bleed out.
你会死的  别这样
You're gonna die. Stop.
向我保证  你不会送我去医院
Promise me you won't take me to the hospital.
我保证
I promise.
看看  她有多爽
Look at how much fun she's having.
那是因为他有两条功能健全的腿
That's because he has two functioning legs,
足以支持她身体的重量
capable of supporting her body weight.
我也有啊
So do I.
是你告诉我你腿上大部分肌肉都被切掉了
You told me most of your muscle was cut out.
那是为博同情  好算便宜点
I was going for the sympathy discount.
最近在用试验药物
Been taking some experimental medicine.
是嘛  我很多客户
Yeah, I got a lot of clients
也在用试验药物
on experimental medicine.
要我证明吗
You want proof?
好吧  这组扩音器
Okay, this amp stack
可比你重得多
weighs way more than you do.
看到没
See?
即使里面是艾德曼合金
Now, even if those implants were made of adamantium,
我也能...
I'd still be able to...
抱歉
Sorry.
腿抽筋了
Cramp.
肯定是
I'm sure.
看来今晚咱们不能共度良宵了
I'm not gonna be needing your services tonight after all.
未伤到肠
Bowel's intact.
下腔静脉也没事
Inferior vena cava's fine.
肝脏有破口  但感觉已凝固
Liver got nicked, but it feels clotted off.
没发现其它内出血迹象
I don't see any other signs of internal bleeding.
那我没事了吗
So I'm okay?
不好说
Define okay.
我未发现出血点
And just because I don't see bleeding
不代表它们就不存在
doesn't mean it's not there.
收缩压105
105 over palp.
我每两分钟测一次你的血压
I'm gonna check your pressure every two minutes.
如果降至90以下
If you dip below 90,
说明肯定有出血点  我们就有麻烦了
it means it is there and we have a problem.
好的
Okay.
抱歉
Sorry.
我得去上班了
I should get to work.
等等  露比
Wait. Ruby.
明早再谈吧
We'll talk more in the morning.
晚安  艾瑞克
Good night, Eric.
你俩闹分手吗
You two breaking up?
她怀孕了
She's pregnant.
我得喝一杯
I need a drink.
是一起抢劫
There was a raid.
安德烈得想法子拖住警察
Andre needed to do something to slow the cops down.
他捅你来分散警察的注意吗
He stabbed you as a distraction?
可惜没用
Didn't work.
警察叫了救护车
Cops called an ambulance,
就把我晾在那里
left me lying there.
行了
Oh, come on.
有话就说
Give me crap.
我知道我说过他不好
I know what I told you about him,
不过我又开始吸毒不是他的错
but it's not his fault I started using again.
怪我自己
It's mine.
怎么了
What?
根据测量结果  你已经死了
According to this, you're dead.
测不到你血压
You have no blood pressure.
脉搏微弱
Barely have a pulse.
我要死了吗
Am I dying?
你一直在说话  神志清楚
You're talking and alert,
就是说你脑部供血正常
so your brain is getting blood.
右上肢脉搏没问题
Pulse in your right arm is fine.
血压也正常
So is your B.P.
喂
Hello.
忙吗
Are you busy?
有点  我...
Yeah, I'm...
正准备出门
I'm about to go out.
太好了  能帮我个忙吗
Great. Can you do me a huge favor?
帮我去趟医院
I need you to go to the hospital
取个便携式超声仪
and check out a portable ultrasound machine for me.
孩子他爹是谁
Who's the father?
我的浴室漏水了
I have a leak in my bathroom,
维修人员要等明早
And my guy won't come
才肯过来看看
take a look at it till tomorrow morning,
而一个应急管道工每小时收费两百块
And an emergency plumber's 200 bucks an hour.
豪斯医生
Dr. House.
里金医生
Dr. Riggin.
我猜这会你的实验应该圆满完成了
Figures you'd be wrapping up the trial by now.
于是特意来向你致以衷心的祝贺
I just wanted to give you a hearty mazel tov.
我研发出这贵得吓人的耗子药
And don't forget the Nobel Prize
可别忘了再给我颁个诺贝尔奖
for developing an incredibly expensive rat poison.
什么意思  怎么了
What do you mean? What happened?
肿瘤
Tumors.
看看这些吧
Just look at these things.
大鼠病发前有什么征兆吗
Any indication the rats were getting sick?
有痉挛现象
Just some cramping.
双腿僵直
Their legs would stiffen up.
行动出现困难
They were having trouble moving around.
我们还以为是它们的机体
We just thought their bodies
正在适应新生的肌肉
were adjusting to the increase in muscle mass,
但差不多在一天之内它们先后毙命
but within a day or so they just started dying.
算了
Oh, well.
下周可以试新药了
Get a new compound to play with next week.
一台便携超声仪
One portable ultrasound.
加辣香肠
Extra pepperoni.
太感谢你了
Thank you so much.
明天我可能会迟到
I might be late tomorrow.
你的袜子没湿
Your socks are dry.
更不巧的是  你的衬衫也没湿
And, unfortunately, so is your shirt,
说明要么是你为了见我而特地更衣
which means you either just changed to greet me,
要么是你打算用它救人
or you need this for something medical.
我也是医生
I am a doctor.
她是我朋友
She's my friend.
我之前是在蹲监狱
I was in prison.
你杀了你亲哥哥
You killed your own brother?
是  那是一段不堪回首的经历
Yes. It was awful and devastating,
但那不是谋杀
but it wasn't murder.
他病了  但求一死
He was sick and he wanted to die,
而我保证过会帮他
and I promised I would help.
别再走来走去了
Now please stop pacing
来帮我找找是哪里出了问题
and help me find this thing.
你跟其他人谈过吗
Have you talked to anybody about it?
我是说  你还好吗
I mean, are you okay?
不好  我可能有主动脉弓动脉瘤
No, I may have an aortic arch aneurysm.
等等  应该是她
Oh, wait, that's her.
要不来帮忙  要不请离开
Either help me or leave.
我看不清楚
Having trouble getting a clear look.
试试从胸骨上部看纵向切面的图像
Try a long axis view from the suprasternal notch.
等下  戴上手套  她有丙肝
Wait! Put on some gloves. She's got Hep-C.
太妙了
Wonderful.
你们两个是狱友吗
Take it you two were cell mates.
朋友而已
Just friends.
她有恩于我
She saved me.
牢中自有牢规
There's a culture in prison.
如果没人告诉你
If you don't have someone to show you
如何获取所需
how to get the stuff you need
如何远离风险
and stay away from the stuff you don't,
你就惨了
you're screwed.
她的手指发绀
Her fingers are turning blue.
你能活动下手指吗
Can you move those?
我胳膊麻了
My arm's starting to go numb.
主动脉弓没问题
Arch of aorta's clear.
这不可能是动脉瘤
This can't be an aneurysm.
或许是从伤口脱落的血凝块
Maybe the wound threw a clot.
检查下腋动脉
Check axillary arteries.
停  就在那里
Stop. Right there.
是个直径五厘米边界模糊的肿块
5 centimeter gooey mass.
不是血凝块  会不会是脂肪瘤
Not a clot. Maybe a lipoma?
那是什么
What the hell is that?
一堆脂肪
Fat-filled sack.
大概是受外伤刺激而变大的
Probably aggravated by the stab wound.
你有注射器吗
You got any syringes in here?
我来找
Give me that.
挨刀的是肚子  又不是胳膊
I was stabbed in my gut, not in my arm.
你失血过多
You lost a lot of blood,
让脂肪瘤有了膨胀空间
gave the lipoma room to swell.
它压迫上肢动脉
It's compressing the arteries in your arm,
阻断了血流
blocking your blood flow.
或许能用针头抽出来一点
Maybe we can suck some of it out.
不是大事  会有点疼
You'll be fine. Little pinch.
那可不是脂肪瘤
That's not lipoma.
我无法理解  她居然会考虑
I don't know why she's even considering
生下我的孩子
having my kid.
她又不了解我
She barely knows me.
只知道我是个秃顶的矮子
All she knows is I'm a short, balding guy.
这甚至不符合进化逻辑
It doesn't even make evolutionary sense.
-你想要这个孩子吗  -不想
- You want her to keep it? - No.
因为你会是个糟糕透顶的老爹
'Cause you'd make a crappy dad.
我说了  我不想要
I said, "No."
你太自私了
You're too selfish.
那是你搞婚外情的原因
That's why you cheated on your wife,
导致你婚姻破裂
why your marriage fell apart--
伙计  我说了
Dude, I said--
我了解你
I know you.
你呆在脱衣舞酒吧
The only reason you're sitting in a strip club,
却不看脱衣舞的唯一原因就是
ignoring the strip club,
你在考虑留下这个孩子
is because you actually are considering it.
可如果世界上没有不负责任的老爹...
Although without crappy dads in the world...
再试着动动手指
Try moving your fingers again.
好的
Good.
这么说已经快抽干净了
Means it's almost drained.
还不够
Not good enough.
我们不知道它还会不会再次膨胀
We don't know if it's gonna come back.
我们不知道是什么引起的
We don't even know what it is--
毒品  病毒  监狱里的有毒物质
drugs, viruses, toxins from that crack house
还有天知道她还去过哪
and god knows where else she's been.
如果是由毒品引起的话
If this were caused by the drugs,
她会出现肾衰竭  心脏问题
she'd have kidney failure, cardiac involvement.
她的丙肝呢
What about her hep-C?
可能摧毁了她的肝脏  失去了合成功能
Could have fried her liver. Loses its synthetic function.
那么她整个身体都会出现肿胀
Then her entire body would be swelling,
不会只是她的胳膊
not just her arm.
那就只剩有毒物质了
That leaves us with toxins.
你是在哪里遭袭的
Where exactly were you when you were attacked?
你又不能去搜毒贩的老窝  那太危险了
You're not doing a home search in a crack den. That's insane.
显然我们没有太多的选择
Apparently, we don't have much of a choice.
那是个犯罪现场  而且不是有毒物质
It's a crime scene, and it's not toxins
也不是病毒或你提到的其它因素引起的
or viruses or anything else you mentioned,
因为这肯定不是偶然
because it's not a coincidence.
她的症状肯定和刀伤有关
Her symptoms have to be related to the stabbing.
会不会是她的身体为了止住伤口流血
What if her body used up all the clotting factors
而消耗了所有的凝血因子
dealing with the stab wound?
可以解释那个血块
Explains the bloody mass.
但若如此  她身体的任何部位都可能出血
But if you're right, she could start bleeding anywhere,
比如她的大脑和心脏
like in her brain or in her heart.
那些东西也会出现在我大脑里吗
One of those things could start growing in my brain?
得送你去医院了
It's time to get you to the hospital.
不
Oh, no.
莱米  你答应过我的
Remy, you promised.
在医院里  不过是能让她躺在病床上
All we'll do at the hospital is stick her in a patient bed
给她输入凝血因子
and give her I.V. clotting factors.
在这里也能做啊
We can do that right here.
但她很可能也就死在这里了
We could also embalm her right here.
我打电话订药  你去拿
I'll call the drugs in. You go pick them up.
如果我是对的  她就没事了
If I'm right, she'll be fine.
我知道你不认识她
Look, I know you don't know her
也不关心她  但是我在乎
and you don't care about her, but I do.
求你了
Please.
躺好  抬高左肩
Lie down, elevate your shoulder.
你说安德烈跟你吸毒没关系
You said Andre wasn't responsible for the drugs.
那你是为什么
What is?
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
不  你知道
Yes, you do.
到底怎么了
What happened to you?
如果你不正视真正的问题
If you don't deal with the real problem--
我来这  是因为你是个医生
I came here because you're a doctor...
我不需要心理医生
Not a shrink.
你手机在震
Your lap is vibrating.
不好意思
Oh, sorry.
是我老板
It's my boss.
可能喝醉了
Probably drunk.
想让我载他回家  让他打车好了
Wants a ride home. He can take a cab.
你有孩子吗
Do you have any kids?
怎么  你有恋母情结吗
Why? You like moms?
我可以当你妈妈
I could be your mommy.
打你的小屁屁
Spank your little ass.
不是  我...
No. I--
如果你怀孕了你会怎么办
What would you do if you got pregnant?
当然不是我的了
Not by me...at all,
假想有这么一个人
but by some hypothetical guy
他不想留着这个假想中的孩子
who didn't want to keep the hypothetical kid.
他用什么方式告诉你
What would be the least awful way
你更容易接受
for him to tell you that?
别说话
Don't talk.
乖乖地看老娘给你跳舞
Just let mama dance for you.
我要送花吗
Should I send flowers?
要在小卡片上写"门诊见"吗
Maybe write the clinic appointment on the little card?
给她个惊喜
Surprise!
我恨我自己
I hate myself.
就没有好办法...
There's just no good way to--
你有这颗痣多长时间了
How long have you had this mole?
它是不对称的
It's asymmetrical.
禁止触摸
No touching.
抱歉
Sorry.
你看过皮肤科医生吗
Have you been to see a dermatologist?
鲍比
Bobby!
我没有碰她  我只是
I wasn't touching her. I was just--
我的天
Oh, god.
不
No.
不  求你不要
No, please don't.
求你  别  把枪放下
Please, please... Put the gun down.
把枪放在地上
Put it down on the ground
走开
and get away!
-迪  -很抱歉
- Dee? - I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
I'm sorry.
迪  怎么回事
Dee, what is it?
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
很抱歉
I'm sorry!
你怎么不在自己床上睡觉
Why aren't you in your bed?
少给我口出狂言
Jibber me jabbers.
我会打得你屁滚尿流
I'll give ye splinters in yer arse,
你个无能鼠辈
Ye mangy bilge rat.
你在看什么
What are you watching?
电视《你个饭桶》
TV, You Bloody Scallywag.
妈妈
Mom!
你最好是快死了
Someone better be dying.
她出现幻觉了  我需要你再去一趟
She hallucinated. I need you to go back out.
我刚有又多要了些凝血因子
I just called in more clotting factor.
就是说  她现在颅内出血
So she's bleeding in her brain now.
用两倍的剂量  她就会没事的
We double up the dose, she'll be fine.
不行
No.
我们得把她送医院
We bring her to the hospital,
做CT确认出血部位
we do a CT scan to locate the bleed,
给她做颅骨钻孔
drill a burr hole in her skull,
这样她才可能会没事
and maybe she'll be fine.
在这里我们也可以做颅骨钻孔
We can drill a burr hole here.
你现在不仅在拿我们的职业生涯冒险
You're not just risking our careers here.
你还可能会二进宫
You could go back to prison.
我向她承诺过
I made a promise.
你承诺过什么
You made a promise?
我不会送她去医院
I will not take her to the hospital.
很好  那我来
Great. Then I will.
不行
No.
我会把你丢开
I'm gonna move you,
然后我会扶起你的朋友
and then I'm gonna pick your friend up,
把她弄到我车里  送她去医院
carry her down to my car, take her to the hospital,
尽力挽救她的性命
and try to save her life.
她得留在这里
She's staying here.
让开
Move.
赶紧让开
Move!
她得去医院
She's going to the hospital.
甜心
Sweetie...
去沙发那边等妈妈  好吗
Go wait for mommy by the couch, okay?
去吧
Go on.
我试过打给其他人
I tried calling everyone else.
你是名单上的最后一位
You were the last one on the list.
能给个理由为什么911不在名单上吗
Any reason why 911 wasn't on the list?
又不是什么紧急情况
It's not an emergency.
没错
Right.
你是要自杀吗
Are you suicidal?
我又没在做高难度手术
I'm not attempting bypass surgery.
肿瘤很小
The tumors are small
靠近表皮
and they're close to the surface.
我以为切除它就像
I thought it'd be like...
切除疣那么简单
Removing a wart.
你就等不到早晨吗
You couldn't wait till morning,
把你的CT给真正的外科医生看看
Bring your CT to an actual surgeon?
外科医生都是蠢货
Surgeons are idiots.
他们只会在肌肉上乱动刀子
They'd just hack away at the muscle
直到他们切除肿瘤
until they get worn out.
也可能是你为自己注射还未通过
Or you're just ashamed you've been injecting a drug
安全试验的药物为耻
that hasn't even gone through safety trials.
这药还未在人体上用过
It's never even been in the human body.
我已经摘除了其中一个肿瘤了
I got one of the tumors.
第二个也快了
The second one is close.
你可以用CT找到第三个肿瘤
You can use the CT to help you find the third.
我要带你去医院
I'm taking you to the hospital.
你就  就帮我切除肿瘤吧
Just--just excise the tumor.
绝对不行
Absolutely not!
把她的头再抬高点
Elevate her head more.
不用麻烦了
Don't bother.
警察会在医院正门守着我的
Cops are gonna be waiting at the front door.
我先进医院
I'll go in first.
我会找个用生命维持设备等死的病人
I'll find a patient on life support who's waiting to die.
我们会以他的名字帮你做检测
We'll use their name on all your tests.
没人会知道你在那里
No one will ever know you're there.
谢了
Thanks.
你的腿怎么了
What happened to your leg?
我想治好它
I was trying to make it better.
他没动脑筋
He was being reckless.
宝贝  坐好了
Sit back, honey.
你不是想治好你的腿
This isn't about making your leg better.
你是想让你的生活回到正轨
It's about making your life better.
又来了
Here we go.
早知道我就打911了
Wish I had called 911.
否则你为什么会冒生命危险
Why else would you risk your life
做这么愚蠢的事情呢
doing something so stupid?
你也知道  我最近遭受了很多挫折
Well, you know, I've had a lot of setbacks lately.
别拿我们俩分手来说事
Don't blame our breakup for this.
你不是因为我才不快乐
You're not unhappy because of me.
你就是不快乐
You're just unhappy.
不快乐的人就会做脑残的事情
Unhappy people do reckless things.
达里恩
Darrien!
别叫了  我头疼
Stop screaming. My head hurts.
我需要你保持清醒  跟我说话
I need you to stay awake. Talk to me.
说什么啊
About what?
你在我房间里尖叫的时候
When you were screaming in my room,
你觉得自己看到什么了
what did you think you saw?
你说"把枪放在地上  走开"
You said, "Put it down on the ground and get away."
听起来像警察说的话
Sounds like a cop.
估计是旧习惯了
Old habits, I guess.
你原本是名警察吗
You were a cop?
那是我还是个清白的人时候的事情了
Back when I was a decent person.
我怎么不知道这事呢  你知道所有...
How do I not know this? You knew everything--
想在监狱里存活就不能抖露出你的"好"履历
Not a good resume when you're trying to survive in prison.
那你在我卧室里是在跟谁说话呢
So who were you talking to in my bedroom?
你为什么一直道歉
Why did you keep apologizing?
因为我很抱歉
Cause I'm sorry.
为什么
For what?
我杀了一个孩子
I killed a kid.
他才十九岁
He was 19.
我最先进入
I went in first.
看见他在摸枪
Saw him going for his gun.
我试图劝他缴械  但是...
I tried to talk him down, but...
他们说我是英雄
They told me I was a hero.
你就是从那时起开始吸毒的吗
So that's when you started using drugs?
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
达里恩
Darrien?
Darrien!
她失去知觉了
She lost consciousness.
前面没车  穿过去吧
There are no cars coming. Just go.
还是红灯  你个饭桶
The light is red, ye bloody scallywag.
别再学海盗说话了
Stop with the pirate talk.
如果你不想让棕胡子的腿
If you don't want brownbeard
最后变成两条木头腿
to end up with two wooden legs,
那最好让你妈妈启动这艘船
better get yer ma to move this ship,
你这卑鄙的舱底鼠
you mangy bilge rat.
难怪了
Of course...
是你让她看那部下流的动画片的
you showed her that filthy cartoon.
你是白痴吗  让三岁小孩看那个
What kind of idiot lets a three-year-old watch that?
如果你想教训我缺乏判断力
If you want to lecture me on my poor judgment,
有些别的事例更有说服力
there would seem to be more relevant examples.
你在这里啊
There you are.
你在贵宾室里待了那么久
You were in the vip room so long,
我还以为你要为那姑娘付房贷呢
I thought you were gonna pay off that girl's mortgage.
我被保镖鲍比扔出来了
I got tossed out by Bobby the bouncer.
你摸她了吗
You touched her?
我在看她的痣
I was looking at her mole.
真是天才  咱们回家吧
Genius. Let's go home.
我想等她出来
I want to wait for the girl,
确保那颗痣没问题
make sure that mole's okay.
要是保镖看到你站在这里
Bobby the bouncer sees you
像个跟踪者一样
standing out here like a stalker,
他会把你打散架的
he's gonna break open your skull.
那颗痣不对称  可能是癌性的
It was asymmetrical. It could be cancerous.
你想被打得散架
You want to get your skull cracked open.
你试图惩罚自己
You're trying to punish yourself.
我想实现医生的誓言
I want to fulfill my oath as a doctor.
你觉得自己是个混蛋
You think you're a screw-up.
觉得自己该打  因为你让一姑娘怀孕了
Because you got a girl pregnant and you deserve to suffer.
可你不必
You don't.
你只需要好好睡一觉  再来处理这事
You just need some sleep and you'll handle this mess.
我们上车吧
Let's get in the car.
她估计很快就下班了
She's probably off work soon.
把钥匙给我  我来开车
Give me the keys. I'll drive.
我搭出租车好了
I'll get a cab.
一切好运
Good luck with everything.
为了维护你朋友你简直失去理智了
You were defending your friend beyond all rationality,
甚至给了她死在你卧室的权利
granting her the right to die in your bedroom.
这真的只是因为一句承诺吗
Was it really all because of a promise?
承诺这词对有些人是有意义的
That word means something to some people.
也不至于这样啊
Not that much.
没发现出血
I don't see the bleed.
把成像部位移到脑干处
I'm moving down to the brain stem.
你向你哥哥保证会为他进行安乐死
You promised your brother you'd euthanize him
你认为只要归咎于承诺本身
and you think you won't feel bad about it
你就不会为此而感到内疚
as long as you can blame it on the promise.
因此你对于信守承诺
That's why you have this twisted obligation
有着如此扭曲的执著
to keep all promises...
否则你小心翼翼建立起来的心理防线
or your carefully constructed defense mechanism
就会崩溃
could crumble down.
我使我哥免遭巨大的痛苦
I saved my brother from a lot of pain.
重建图像是阴性的
Reconstructed image is clear.
达里恩的大脑中没有出血
There's no bleed in Darrien's brain.
图像模糊了  她醒了吗
Image just blurred. Did she wake up?
她正在发抖
she's shivering.
她肯定是发烧了
She must have a fever.
感染吗
Infection?
不可能是刺伤造成的
It couldn't be from the stabbing.
必须是由刺伤造成的
It has to be from the stabbing.
不  不可能发展得这么快
No, it couldn't be acting that quickly.
那她究竟是怎么了
Well, then what's wrong with her?
你的心率已经超过120了
Your heart rate's over 120.
你皮肤湿冷  我想你快要休克了
You're clammy. I think you're going into shock.
你是否感觉头昏眼花
Are you lightheaded?
我没事
I'm fine.
你看了最新棕胡子那集了吗
Did you see the new brownbeard episode?
很滑稽
It was so funny.
那集很差劲
No, it was so lame.
一船的男海盗
Got a boat full of guy pirates
却让女海盗去走跳板
and they make the girl pirate walk the plank.
她浮起来了
She floated.
那是因为她咪咪很大
That's 'cause she had big boobies.
所以他应该留着她才对
That's why he should have kept her.
你得赶紧做手术  护士都跑哪里去了
We've got to get you into surgery. Where is that nurse?
瑞秋  咱们去找护士
Rachel, let's go find the nurse.
凌晨2点
2:00 A.M.
感谢你回我电话
Nice of you to call me back.
我和奇斯正和病人在医院里
Chase and I are in the hospital with a patient.
你们黔驴技穷了
You've completely run out of ideas
打给我就为了给你们出主意
and you're calling me to bail you out.
我太感动了  把情况告诉我
I'm touched. Hit me.
请说指令
Command, please.
拨通露比
Call Ruby.
您要拨打露比的移动电话吗
Would you like to call Ruby on mobile?
不
No.
她是否服药了  快克[毒品]不算
She on any medication... besides crack?
她在监狱时一直注射干扰素
She was taking interferon in prison,
因此我猜测她患丙肝至少有十年了
so I'm guessing she's had Hep-C for at least ten years.
我是不是也能猜一下
Can I guess stuff too?
这样的话做诊断就容易多了
'cause that's gonna make the diagnosis really easy.
监狱的医务室不知道要保存病历
Prison infirmary isn't known for stellar record keeping.
现在我们也没办法问病人
And we can't exactly ask the patient.
那看来她已经进入昏迷前期了
Yeah, that would have been pre-coma.
但你们怎么知道
But how could you have known
病人已经进入昏迷前期了
that it would affect her that way?
我们一开始没发现任何异常  直到
We didn't think we had anything mysterious until--
会不会是肾癌释放的栓子
How about renal cancer throwing clots?
-尿检呈阴性  -太糟了
- Urinalysis was negative. - That's too bad.
我就想出这么一个好主意
'cause that was my one big idea.
真的吗
Really?
豪斯
House?
豪斯  你还在吗
House, you there?
再跟我说说病人的情况
Tell me more about the patient.
进监狱前她是做什么的
What was she doing before prison?
警察
She was a cop.
正当防卫时射杀了一个孩子
Shot a kid in self defense,
一直心怀内疚不能自拔
never got over the guilt,
从此开始磕药然后被抓
started taking drugs, and got busted.
你还真会挑重点
Way to bury the lead.
枪击事件是什么时候发生的
How long ago was the shooting?
我不知道  怎么了
I'm not sure. Why?
再者  你只是假设她患丙肝十年了
Again, you assumed she's had Hep-C for ten years.
去查出她何时杀了那孩子
Find out when she shot the kid,
你就能知道她何时开始磕药
you'll find out when she started taking drugs,
以及她究竟何时感染的丙肝
and when she actually contracted the Hep-C.
你认为这些跟她的现状有关联吗
And you think this is relevant?
比你们现在知道的信息更有用
It's more relevant than what you got now,
那些根本一文不值
which is squat.
我屋里来了三位美女
Three chicks just came into my bedroom.
先挂了
I got to go.
请说指令
Command, please.
拨通瑞秋
Call Rachel.
您是要拨打瑞秋的移动电话吗
Would you like to call Rachel on the cell phone?
不
No.
你想干什么
What the hell?
我真是个医生  我只是想
I really am a doctor. I just wanted--
想偷摸我吗  离我远点
Cop another feel? Get away from me.
不  是那颗痣  我不过想
No, that mole. I just wanted--
求你  别叫保镖
Please, don't call Bobby.
请你...
Just...
-冷静点  -闭嘴
- Calm down.  - Shut up!
变态  跪下
Sick perv! Get down on your knees!
你以为我是开玩笑吗
You think I'm kidding?
转过去  跪下
Turn around and get down on your knees!
求求你别
Please don't.
-我说了闭嘴  -上帝保佑  上帝保佑
- I said shut up!  - Please, please please...
你以为你是第一个自视特殊的人吗
You think you're the first guy who thought he was special?
上帝保佑  上帝保佑
Please, please, please...
你以为你能为所欲为吗
You think you can do whatever you want?
我不会再犯傻了
I am not going through that again!
上帝保佑  上帝保佑
Please... Please...Please...
找到什么吗
Find anything?
令人震惊啊
Shockingly...
一个朋克小子摸枪时被警察击毙
A punk kid getting shot pulling a gun on a cop
没能成为国家新闻
did not make national news.
你的脖子还好吧
Is your neck okay?
挺好  没事
Yeah, it's fine.
我去给你拿些冰
I'll get you some ice.
我说过没事了
I said it was fine.
我不该那么大力抓你的
I shouldn't have grabbed you so hard.
你是迫于无奈
You had to.
你说得对  全都对
You were right... about everything.
有了
Oh, I got something.
达里恩肯定用过别的姓
Darrien must have had a different last name then.
她肯定结过婚
She must have been married.
2008年  可能吗
2008? Is that possible?
我们从没谈论过她进去多久
We never actually talked about how long she'd been in.
豪斯是对的
House was right.
她可能才得了丙肝没多久
She could have only had her Hep-C for a few years.
若非检查结果显示她的丙肝是慢性的
There's no way the prison would have prescribed interferon
监狱不会向她提供干扰素
unless the lab showed her Hep-C to be chronic.
什么能让新乙肝看起来像是旧病呢
So what makes new Hep-C looks like old Hep-C?
如果她有寄生虫呢
What if she got a parasite?
丙肝让她易感寄生虫
The Hep-C made her susceptible
而寄生虫又加剧了她的肝脏病变
and the parasite sped up the liver damage.
阿米巴虫
Entamoeba.
如果寄生虫在寄生虫囊中的话
If they were in a parasitoma,
刺伤可能把它们放了出来
the stab wound could have freed them,
让它们随血液肆意流动  破坏组织
sent them coursing through her bloodstream, wreaking havoc.
给她输一袋甲硝唑
A single bag of metronidazole.
如果我们是对的  几小时后她就能醒了
If we're right, she could wake up from the coma in a few hours.
为您准备好了
They're ready for you.
等等
Wait.
我想让你也进来
I want you in there.
我不是外科医生
I'm not a surgeon.
什么也帮不上
There's nothing I can do.
你可以确保  那白痴屠夫
Well, you can make sure that... idiot butcher
不做不必要的切除
doesn't cut more than he needs to.
你已经在手术协议上签字了
You already signed a release.
他会做他该做的
He's gonna do what he needs to do.
是啊  可如果那包括截肢
Yeah, and if that involves chopping off my leg...
我希望能肯定那该死的决定是必要的
I want to be sure that that's damn well necessary.
豪斯
House...
我不相信他
I don't trust him.
我相信你
I trust you.
能听到我说话吗
Can you hear me?
可以
Yeah.
你肝脏里有寄生虫
You had parasites in your liver.
可能是因不干净的针头或是监狱环境
Probably from a dirty needle or prison...
又或者...谁知道呢
or...  who knows what?
刺伤使情况变得更糟糕...
The stabbing made it worse...
但你会好起来的
But you're gonna be okay.
我很抱歉  但我们必须这么做
I'm sorry. We had to.
我告诉过你  我不能回去
I told you I couldn't go back.
我真不该相信你
I shouldn't have trusted you.
我从没喜欢过你
I never liked you.
我和你在一起  只因我身陷囹圄
I killed time with you 'cause I was locked in a cage.
你不过是我用来消遣的
You were a distraction.
有人能说说话  好让我不用...
Someone to talk to so I didn't have to think about...
胡思乱想
Everything else.
你是在说气话  我明白的
You're lashing out... I get it.
但一个月后  你会感谢我的
But in a month, you'll thank me.
或许你不会  我不知道
Or maybe you won't. I don't know.
但是...
But...
我知道我救了你的命
I know I saved your life.
他会好起来吗
Is he going to be okay?
他会好起来的
He'll be fine.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
我希望豪斯还能来跟我一起玩
I wish house still came over to play.
也许你该给他写封信
Maybe you should write him a letter.
想写吗
Want to do that?
好的  现在就写
Okay, let's do it.
露比
Ruby.
你看上去好糟糕  而且闻起来...
You look like hell and you smell like...
我想了很多
I've been doing a lot of thinking.
你身上沾的是亮片吗
Is that glitter on you?
听我说完
Just hear me out.
我还在做整形的时候
Back when I still had my practice,
遇过一位病人  50岁的男性
this patient came in, 50-year-old guy,
来做腹部拉皮
wanted a tummy tuck.
可是在做准备工作的时候
But when we do some prelim work,
我们发现他的胃里布满了肿瘤
we discover that his stomach is filled with cancer.
于是我非但没能让他在海滩秀健美
So instead of telling him that he's gonna look great at the beach,
还得告诉他大限将至
I got to tell him that he's dying.
你去脱衣舞夜总会了吗
Were you at a strip club?
听我说完  最奇怪的是
Please. The weird part was
我甚至比他更难接受事实
I was more upset about the whole thing than he was.
以至于他反过来安慰我
He actually had to calm me down.
他说他有非常优秀的子女  教养得法
Said he had great kids, raised them right,
因为有了他们
knew that because of them,
这世界会更美好  他死而无憾
he was leaving the world a better place.
昨晚我以为自己会死掉
I thought I might die last night.
在脱衣舞夜总会吗
At a strip club?
是的  我当时在脱衣舞夜总会
Yes, I was at a strip club.
昨晚事发时
And while it was happening,
我一直想着那位病人
I kept thinking about that patient
无比希望我能够像他一样坦然
and how I wish I was like him.
我想要这个孩子
I want to have this baby.
达里恩射杀那孩子是迫不得已
Darrien had to shoot that kid.
她做得对  完全合理
It was the right thing. Completely justified.
可是那都没有用
But it didn't matter.
她为忘却这件事毁了自己的生活
She destroyed her life trying to forget.
我好怕我也会变成她那样
I'm afraid that's what's gonna happen to me.
你得找人谈谈
You really should talk to someone.
我找心理治疗师谈过了  没有用
I've talked to a therapist. It didn't help.
那就找个不是心理治疗师的人谈谈
Well, maybe you should talk to someone who isn't a therapist.
你真以为你对杀了人以后的生活是什么滋味
Do you really think you have any idea what it's like
能有一丝的了解吗
to live with something like this?
去喝杯咖啡吧
Let's grab a coffee.
熬夜了
Late night?
没有  只是早上没喝咖啡而已
No. Just haven't had my coffee yet.
呵欠传染
Sympathetic yawn.
门诺教小信徒寻妓途中发病  无奇不有
Amish kid collapsed while picking up a hooker. Top that.
豪斯昨晚来电话没接到
Missed a call from House last night.
他来了吗
He in?
你很走运
You're lucky.
你怎么在这
What are you doing here?
你期待看到其他人吗
You hoping for someone else?
辣护士
Hot nurse,
美助手
candy striper...
最好是不讲英语
someone who doesn't speak English.
也不会评判我的人
someone who doesn't speak judgmental.
有封给你的信
You've got mail.
"希望你的腿好些了"
"I hope your leg feels better
"希望我们很快又能做朋友"
"And I hope we can be friends again soon,
"你个饭桶"
You bloody scallywag."
我得撒尿
I have to pee.
是个好兆头
That's a good sign.
我又不是小孩
I'm a big boy.
对  你不是小孩
Of course you are.
你是混蛋
You're an ass.
为哪遭呢  是腿刚手术就要走路
What, for trying to walk on a freshly mangled leg?
给自己做手术
Performing surgery on myself?
还是自以为可以用老鼠药
For thinking I could solve my emotional problems
解决个人情感问题
with rat medicine?
你唠叨也就罢了
If you're gonna nag,
至少费心给个准确原因嘛
at least have the decency to be specific.
来
Come on.
听我说
Listen to me.
你不能这样下去了
You can't keep going like this.
必须做出改变
Something has to change.
我能先撒尿吗
Can I pee first?
我知道
I know.